Tomas Madariaga

1311 Bonita Ave, Berkeley CA 94709 +1 858 262 1899

madariaga.tomas@gmail.com

PROFILE

www.tomasmadariaga.com - es.linkedin.com/in/tomasmadariaga/en - www.github.com/tomasmax

Full Stack Software Engineer, PM, IT consultant with 4+ years working experience in several Start-ups and in a Big B2B consulting company with a multi-cultural background (Europe & USA). Computer Science & Industrial Engineer. Agile Project Management MSc. Big Thinker, Lifelong Learner, Entrepreneur, Business & Result oriented. Ability to learn new prog languages, frameworks and technologies quickly. High level of RoR, Node.js Java, JS, Angular2, React, React-Native. Willing to create new prototypes, products & solutions. Fluent in English, native Spanish and Basque, medium in French.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer & Product Manager. San Francisco, Moovit

August 2016 - Present

- Work hand in hand with product, engineering and business development team to overhaul www.moovitapp.com 5.0
 version release for #1 transit App Worldwide present in 67 Countries, 1200 Cities, with 45+ Million users and \$80 Millions of Investment.
- Web trip planner Front End development (React, Angular2) and corporation's website development (HTML5, JavaScript) for wining SEO, working closely to the UX/UI teams and bring wireframes & design to life.
- Data mine Moovit user's information and develop data visualization products (Tableau, D3).
- Serve as product manager to translate new features into technical requirements. App & Web prototyping.

Mobile & GIS Full Stack Engineer and Consultant. Spain, Indra

January 2015 - July 2016

- Consultancy and development of a Windows tablet & Android several utility companies network. ESRI GIS back end with JBOSS server. It currently supports the management of more than one million supply points for EDP, over 9,600 miles of distribution network, half a million network elements and 90 maintenance teams.
- Android, Java, .NET Desk & Web development and B2B Mobile & GIS consulting.

Freelance Project Management Coach. Bilbao, Spain, Fondo Formacion Euskadi

May - July 2015

Created a MOOC to increase France & Spain Coworking Space Managers Project Management efficiency, <u>PIRECOW</u> project.

Lead Software Engineer & Project Manager, Bilbao, Spain, Grupo Urbegi

February 2013 - December 2014

- Web Full Stack Engineer, Back End & Front End development using RoR, HTML5, JS, AngularJS and Heroku & AWS. Design and implement RESTful APIs. Leading tech projects for different customers (Agile & Scrum).
- Managed & developed <u>Council of Bizkaia's loan requests</u> filtering web service, allowing to reduce their response time: Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS and AWS.
- Development of a <u>Crowdfunding platform</u>. Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS, PayPal, Stripe and AWS.
- Mediapost Group rebranding consultancy, websites design, development & SEO.

Freelance Web Developer & Designer & Marketing

September - December 2013

- Connect a financial social online game with Facebook.
- Designed advertisements and marketing strategies to introduce a new IT product in the Spanish market.

Software Engineer Intern - Ruby on Rails, Java. Bilbao, Techabout

October 2011 - July 2012

2016

• Meetabout entrepreneurial project Front & Back end development in Ruby on Rails, Java OSGi, HTML5, JS, jQuery.

EDUCATION

Advanced Project Management Postgraduate Degree, University of Barcelona, Spain	2014
PMBOK, PMP, Prince2, Lean Project Management, Six Sigma. Agile methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban	
MSE in Computer Science, GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain	2010 – 2013
MSE in Business Engineering, (Erasmus), Solvay Brussels School, Brussels, Belgium	2012 – 2013
MSE in Industrial Engineering (Business Management), GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto	2010 – 2013
BSc in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2 University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain	2007 – 2010

COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

<u>Machine</u>	Lea	rning	Specia	lizatior	ر, Unive	ersity of	Wash	nington,	Coursera			
					_							

Big Data Specialization, University of San Diego, Coursera 2016

Agile PM Foundation Certification, APMG International 2015

	Programming Mobile Services for Android Handheld Systems: Concurrency by Vanderbilt University on Coursera Bizkaia Talentia Program, Selected because of my skills and academic record. 2013						
	Software Engineering for Software as a Service, University of California, Berkeley, Coursera	2013					
	Ingenio: Innovation, Creativity and Entrepreneurship Program, University of Deusto, Bilbao	2011					
TECHNICAL SKILLS	Java, C/C++, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular2, React, React-Native, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS SEO. Android and Cordova (Phonegap). MVC architecture. Professional experience in Back-end, Front-end, AW Heroku. Proficient with GIT and SVN. TDD. SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DB. AWS Big Data, Ta Pentaho and Rapidminer.	VS and					
ADDITIONAL	Coursera's Global Translator Community (GTC) Volunteer, translate subtitles for course lecture videos.						
EXPERIENCE &	University of Deusto Business IX Forum Employment and Entrepreneurship Business Simulator winner.						
AWARDS	<u>Ironhack program</u> Ambassador at the University of Deusto, helping founders to publicize it in Bilbao.	2014					